Paula Rodríguez Cloud engineer

- ★ linkedin.com/pauloba
- ★ github.com/pauloba
- ★ stackoverflow.com/pauloba

I have a degree in Computer science from Vigo University.

In 2017 I got into Cloud Computing and I've been working with Docker, kubernetes, Anthos service mesh, Terraform, Terragrunt, Helm, Jenkins, jfrog, prometheus, grafana, datadog, sonarQube, anchore.

I have hands-on experience in technical support, system administration and architecture on GCP and AWS.

Tech stack

Kubernetes

Terraform

Jenkins

Docker

Helm

SQL

git

Scripting

Python

Bash

Methodologies

IaC + CI/CD

Kaizen

Agile - Scrum

Git flow

Peer review

Merge Requests

DevSecOps

FinOps

Soft skills

Empathy

Teamwork

Work ethic

Critical thinking

Active listening

Documentation

Resourcefulness

Experience

Vodafone [Oct 2023 - now] Platform engineer

Configuration and administration of AWS cloud infra resources using DevOps practices. Collaboration with architectural decisions for business solutions and platforms.

Designing blueprints for multi-tenant platform capabilities, defining tenant roll-out strategies, writing infra as code and designing and configuring pipelines for apps and infra releases.

FonYou [Jul 2021 - Sep 2023] Cloud Sysadmin

Deployment, operation and support for cloud-based production systems, ensuring the availability, performance, scalability and security of the systems.

Automation of processes and operations + support and maintenance of company-developed applications.

Google through Webhelp [Jan 2019 - June 2021]

Subject Matter Expert

Help customers troubleshoot and fix GCP integrations.

Bug reporting, and bug quality review.

Mentor and guide colleagues to improve the SLAs, SLOs and SLIs.

Create, improve and maintain internal documentation.

Internal training for the infrastructure team.

Languages Experience

Spanish - native English - proficient

Education

Computer science degree
at UVigo [2012 - 2016]
Final project
pauloba/latch-plugin-mediawiki

High level trade school, Computer Programming at CPR Daniel Castelao [2003 - 2005]

Professional training course: Java Programmer and analyst 11 months [2011]

Conferences

Organizing committee

r2con [since 2017]

Merchandising
Schedule planning
Website
Community manager
Organizing speakers/trainers
Audio testing w/music artists

Google through Sellbytel [Aug 2017 - Jan 2019]

Technical Solutions Representative

Triage, diagnosis and solve issues related to GCP services, through email, phone and videoconference.

Experience with a Salesforce-based ticketing system.

Technologies: GCE, GKE, VPC networks, Container Registry, Deployment manager, Pub/Sub, GCP APIs, IAM & Security.

Enxendra Technologies [Nov 2016 – Apr 2017]

Level 2 support and QA unit testing

Patch deployment, UNIX sysadmin (syslog, tomcat, crontab, ssh).

Java unit testing with Groovy and Spock.

Experience with the Atlassian stack: Jira, confluence, bitbucket.

Technologies: docker, IntelliJ, eclipse, SoapUI, postman, MySQL, Java, Ant, Maven, SpringBoot, Groovy and Spock.

Telefónica Security Op. Center

[Nov 2015 - Oct 2016] Level 2 security technician

Coordination with CSIRT / CERT, ISPs, web hostings, registrars and registrants to stop and prevent global fraud attempts.

Incident reporting: analysis and reports for final customers.

Real time network monitoring and security incident analysis with Cisco FirePOWER/SourceFire/FireSight sources for QRadar.

QRadar (IBM SIEM) rule adjustment to fine-tune detections.

Online fraud prevention: referer analysis, bank transfer analysis, monitoring of suspicious phishing connections.

Real time analysis and mitigation for Bank Trojans, halcash.

Experience with the SIRIOS ticketing system and ITSM Remedy.

Experience

National Association for Information Security

[Jan - Sept 2015] General Secretary

The **project** was motivated by approval of **BOE-A-2015-344**

Website sysadmin via Wordpress panel and ssh.

Merchandising design w/Gimp+Inkscape: t-shirts, banners, logo.

Vigo University [2010 – 2013] Sysadmin

Installation, config. and maintenance of the Campus softw/hard.

Management of LDAP systems, SquirrelMail, print servers, network monitoring software.

Restoration and recovery of hardware from old computers.

Network backup management with Clonezilla + Norton Ghost.

Tech support for students and teachers of the Campus labs.

Self-employment [2007 - 2015] Teacher

English and mathematics teacher for high school students.